<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ivan Santos Matas</title>
    <link>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ivan Santos Matas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fancy interactive tables with reactable in R</title>
      <link>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/interactive-tables-reactable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 12:00:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/interactive-tables-reactable/</guid>
      <description>Creating visually appealing tables and visualizations is an asset for any data analyst, especially when the findings have to be presented to the stakeholders or, in general, to a broad audience. In this way, R has some libraries that make this really simple. That is the case with reactable library, which makes it very easy to design very attractive interactive tables. I’ll be using this library along with reactablefmtr, which adds even more functionalities to create these tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market basket analysis with R</title>
      <link>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/market-basket-analysis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 12:00:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/market-basket-analysis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Market basket analysis focuses on finding associations between combinations of values in a dataset, using unsupervised algorithms such as apriori algorithm. A key advantage of using this method is the ability to establish relationships by only taking into account the aggregated purchasing patterns of consumers, like sets of receipts.
In essence, the apriori algorithm is a data mining method that tries to identify patterns in the data to create a set of rules such that, given a set of elements, it tries to identify those items that tend to appear when we observe the purchase of another item, or a set of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL: Analysing train service data</title>
      <link>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/sql-eda-train-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 12:00:00 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanniius.github.io/portfolio/post/sql-eda-train-service/</guid>
      <description>For months I&amp;rsquo;ve been scraping some essential data about commuter and regional trains serviced by Renfe, the main railway provider in Catalonia, such as train schedules or tracking data.
Serving about 350,000 daily rides on weekdays, Renfe&amp;rsquo;s service has been usually refered as very poor, unpunctual, and unreliable. To test these feelings, I&amp;rsquo;ll perform an exploratory data analysis (EDA) on the scraped data using PostgreSQL syntax to query the data directly from the database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
